A Guide to the Environmental Grantmakers Association records FA1143
Rockefeller Archive Center
Environmental Grantmakers Association records
1987-2011
Rockefeller Archive Center
Environmental Grantmakers Association
FA1143
13.6 Cubic Feet 22 letter document size boxes and 4 standard record storage boxes.
Arrangement
The material remains in original order.
Scope and Contents
Type of records include: Reports, publications, newspaper articles, correspondence, reprints, maps, CDs, and monographs
Conditions Governing Access
This collection, including financial records more than 20 years old, is open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
Biographical / Historical
The Environmental Grantmakers Association was formed in 1987 after a meeting in Washington, D. C. of environmental funders who had common interests and wanted to learn about other organizations. It resulted in a 12 member foundation from across the United States that discussed and exchanged ideas from their home organizations. Over the years the foundation has grown to over 200 members from around the world.
Some of their notable programs have been: nurtured working groups and responsive projects; held Federal, State, and Regional Policy Briefings; produced research publications for members, a peer-edited semi-annual EGA Journal; organized a variety of lectures, site visits, leadership trainings; maintained email listservs for the quick sharing of ideas and questions; implemented organizational reviews and strategic plans; facilitated community and collaboration through the work of volunteer committees; and supported and challenged the membership in their work.
- 3rd Quarter Financial Statement, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted – Open in 2018
- Financial Statistics (Tables) (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Balance Sheets, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Balance Sheets, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Francis Marion Hotel, 1997 May 1 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Consolidated Schedule - Support, Revenue, and Expenses, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Financial Reports, 1993 January 1-December 31 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Grant Letters, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Greenvote, Report, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Environmental Crimes, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Washington, D. C. Campaign Proposal, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- PEER (Public Employees for Environmental Responsibility) Planning Meeting, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- PEER (Public Employees for Environmental Responsibility), Incorporation Papers, 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- PEER (Public Employees for Environmental Responsibility), Proposal Draft, 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Religion & Environment Booklet, 1993-1995 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Religion & Environment Booklet, Faxes, 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Incorporation, 1995-1996 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Operational Review, Findings and Recommendations for Managing Organizational Growth, 1999 February (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Management Board, Ballots 2000, 1996, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Information Brochure (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Membership Surveys, Results, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Membership Surveys, Organizations' Responses, 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 22-23)
- Consumption Surveys, Results, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Consumption Surveys, Fall Treat, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Consumption Surveys, Fall Treat, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Guidelines, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Membership Policy Comments, 1988-1991, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 28-29)
- Mission/Guidelines, 1987, 1989-1990 (Box 3, Folder 30)
- By-Laws, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 31)
- Fall Retreat, Film Series, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Dellums, Ronald V., 1999-2002 (Box 3, Folder 33)
- Biltmore Estate, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Program Committee, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 35)
- Maddens Pre-Conference Site Visit, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 36)
- Program Committee, Preliminary Information, 2001-2002 (Box 3, Folder 38)
- Fall Retreat Schedule, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 39)
- Program Committee, San Francisco, 2002 February 11-14 (Box 3, Folder 40)
- Fall Retreat, Transportation, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 41)
- Grove Park Inn, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 42)
- Program Committee, Grove Park Meeting, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 43)
- Pike, Lisa, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 44)
- Fall Retreat, Asilomar, Lodging, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 45)
- Day Trips, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 46)
- Site Coordinator, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 47)
- Fall Retreat, Web Links, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 48)
- Smith, Linda, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 49)
- Asilomar Conference Center, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 50)
- Rice, Juliet, Asilomar, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 51)
- Fall Retreat, Cultural Evening, 1999 October 24-27 (Box 4, Folder 52)
- Additions/Changes, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 53)
- Beer & Wine, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 54)
- Asilomar, AV, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 55)
- Host Committee, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 56)
- Event Locations, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 57)
- Participant Lists, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 58)
- Fall Retreat, Additional Workshops, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 59)
- Ad Hocs, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 60)
- Program Committee, 1998-1999 (Box 4, Folder 61)
- Program Committee, Seattle, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 62-63)
- Program Committee, Minutes, 1999 March (Box 5, Folder 64)
- Program Committee, Monterey, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 65)
- Member Sponsored Workshop Proposals, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 66)
- Fall Retreat, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 67)
- Workshop Information, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 68)
- Workshops, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 69)
- Host Committee, 2000-2001 (Box 5, Folder 70)
- Program Committee, Santa Monica, 2001 March 12-13 (Box 5, Folder 71)
- Program Committee, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 72)
- Food Committee, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 73)
- Sense of Place, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 74)
- Plenaries, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 75)
- Bedolfe, Beto, The Shaman and the An-Tap, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 76)
- Fall Retreat, Contacts, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 77)
- Site Coordinator, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 78)
- Program Committee, Brainerd, MN, 2000-2001 (Box 6, Envelope 79)
- Speakers, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 80)
- Agendas & Charts, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 81)
- Site Visits, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 82)
- Fall Retreat, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 83)
- Pre-Retreat Visit, Madden's on Gull Lake, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 84)
- Madden's on Gull Lake, Rooms, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 85)
- Travel, Brainerd, MN, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 86)
- Green Energy, 2000-2001 (Box 6, Folder 87)
- Program Committee, Aspen, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 88)
- Site Visits, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 89)
- Changes & Additions, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 90)
- Workshop Forms, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 91)
- Transportation, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 92)
- Seeger, Pete, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 93)
- Shaw, Jonathan, 1999-2000 (Box 6, Folder 94)
- Host Committee, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 95)
- Murnion, Kathy, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 96)
- W Hotel, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 97)
- EGA (Environmental Grantmakers Association) Institute, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 98)
- Roommates, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 99)
- Fall Retreat, Maps and Brochures, Mohonk Mountain House (Box 7, Folder 100)
- Film Information, 1997-2000 (Box 7, Folder 102)
- Facilitation Materials, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 102)
- Professor "Louie" & The Crowmatix, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 103)
- Volunteers, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 104)
- Room Pick-up, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 106)
- Mohonk Rooms, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 106)
- Room Set-up Sheets, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 107)
- Liability Forms, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 108)
- International Briefing, 1999-2001 (Box 7, Folder 109-110)
- Federal Policy Briefing, Logistics, 2000-2001 (Box 7, Folder 111)
- Federal Policy Briefing, Speakers, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 112)
- Federal Policy Briefing, 1999-2001 (Box 8, Folder 113)
- State of the States, Site Visits, 2002 (Box 8, Folder 114)
- Issue Briefing: Energy, Moderator Packet (Box 8, Folder 115)
- Misrach, Richard, 2002 (Box 8, Folder 116)
- State of the States, New Orleans, 2002 March 4-7, 2000-2002 (Box 8, Folder 117)
- State of the States, Miami Beach, Details, 2000 (Box 8, Folder 118)
- State of the States, 1999-2000 (Box 8, Folder 119-120)
- State of the States, Speakers, 1999-2000 (Box 8, Folder 121)
- EGA Award, 2000-2001 (Box 8, Folder 122)
- EGA Award, 2000-2002 (Box 9, Folder 123-125)
- EGA Award, Grove Park, 2002 (Box 9, Folder 126)
- Management Board Meeting, Minutes, 1991-2000 (Box 9, Folder 127)
- Management Committee Meeting, 1989, 1991-1993 (Box 9, Folder 128-130)
- Management Committee Meeting, 1993-1998 April 27 (Box 10, Folder 131-139)
- Management Committee Meeting, 1998 September 27-1999 September 16-17 (Box 11, Folder 140-143)
- Management Board Meeting, 2000 January 18-19-2000 September 13 (Box 11, Folder 144-146)
- Management Board Meeting, 2001 January 22-23-2003 September 24 (Box 12, Folder 147-154)
- Management Board Meeting, 2004 January 7-9-2005 July 12-13 (Box 13, Folder 155-159)
- Management Board Meeting, 2005 September 28-29-2006 October 11 (Box 14, Folder 160-165)
- Management Board Meeting, 2007 April 28-September 26 (Box 15, Folder 166-167)
- New Management Board Member Packet, 2004 (Box 14, Folder 168)
- Management Committee Strategic Planning Meeting, 1997 April 7-8 (Box 15, Folder 169)
- Program Committee Meeting, 1996 January 24-26 (Box 15, Folder 170)
- Program Committee, Planning Workbook, 2007 (Box 15, Folder 171)
- Strategic Framework, 2009 January-July (Box 15, Folder 172-173)
- Board of Directors Meeting, 2008 February 5-2008 July 22-23 (Box 15, Folder 174-175)
- Board of Directors Meeting, 2008 September 20-2009 July 14-15 (Box 16, Folder 176-178)
- New Board of Directors Member Welcome & Orientation Packet, 2008 (Box 15, Folder 179)
- Finance Committee Report, 2007 (Box 15, Folder 180)
  Restricted - open in 2018
- State of the States, 2002 March 3-5 (Box 15, Folder 181)
- Fall Retreat, 2000-2001 (Box 16, Folder 182-183)
- Membership Committee, 1999, 2002-2004 (Box 16, Folder 184-185)
- By-Laws, 2008 July 23 (Box 16, Folder 186)
- Board Assessment, 1999 (Box 16, Folder 187)
- Board Documents, 1999, 2001-2002, 2006 (Box 16, Folder 188)
- Operational Review, 1999 (Box 16, Folder 189)
- Fall Retreat, 1991 (Box 16, Folder 190)
- Getting Strategic: A Retreat for Funders in the Environmental and Community Development, 1991 October 29-30 (Box 16, Folder 191)
- Reauthorization of Selected Federal Environmental Legislation, 1992 (Box 16, Folder 192)
- Fall Retreat, Islamorada, FL, 1992 (Box 17, Folder 193)
- Fall Retreat, Rio Rico, AZ, 1993, 1992-1993 (Box 17, Folder 194)
- Great Lakes Environmental Grantmakers, 1994 (Box 17, Folder 195-196)
- Congressional Briefing, 1997 February 3-4 (Box 17, Folder 197)
- Fall Retreat, Mount Washington, NH, 1994 (Box 17, Folder 198)
- Pre-Conference Retreat, Inverness, CA, 1995 April 28-30 (Box 17, Folder 199)
- Fall Retreat, Charleston, SC, 1996 (Box 17, Folder 200)
- Fall Retreat, Girwood, Alaska, 1997 (Box 17, Folder 201)
- Program Committee, 1997 (Box 17, Folder 202)
- Fall Retreat, Houston, TX, 1998 (Box 17, Folder 203)
- State of the Environment, 1998 (Box 17, Folder 204)
- Federal Policy Briefing, 1999 February 8-9 (Box 17, Folder 205)
- Fall Retreat, Monterey, CA, 1999, 1998-1999 (Box 17, Folder 206)
- State of the States, 2000 March 1-2 (Box 17, Folder 207)
- Fall Retreat, New Paltz, NY, 2000 (Box 17, Folder 208)
- Institute Briefing Book, Sustainable Forestry and Certification, 2000 September 10 (Box 17, Folder 209)
- EGA-Consultative Group on Biological Diversity (CGBD), Funders Network on Trade and Globalization Briefing, 2000 December 11-13 (Box 18, Folder 210)
- Federal Policy Briefing & EGA-Consultative Group on Biological Diversity (CGBD)-The Peace & Security Funders Group (PSFG), International Policy Briefing, 2001 February 5-7 (Box 18, Folder 211)
- Environmental Briefing at the 2001 Council on Foundations Confernece, 2001 April 28-2002 April 28 (Box 18, Folder 212-213)
- Fall Retreat, Brainerd, MN, 2001 (Box 18, Folder 214)
- EGA & Council on Foundations, Wetlands and Bayou Site Visit, 2002 February 2 (Box 18, Folder 215)
- State of the States, 2002 March 4-5, 2008 February 5-7, 2010 February 23-24 (Box 18, Folder 216-218)
- Fall Retreat, Ashville, NC, 2002 (Box 18, Folder 219)
- Great Lakes Funders Meeting, 2002 July 15 (Box 18, Folder 220)
- Rogers, Jane, Retirement Reception at Fall Retreat, 2002 (Box 18, Folder 221)
- Federal Policy Briefing & EGA-Consultative Group on Biological Diversity (CGBD)-The Peace & Security Group (PSFG)-Funders' Network on Trade and Golbalization (FNTG) International Policy Briefing, 2003 February 3-5 (Box 18, Folder 222)
- Fall Retreat, Ottawa, Canada, 2003 (Box 18, Folder 223)
- Fall Retreat, Kauai, Hawaii, 2004 (Box 18, Folder 224)
- Federal Policy Briefing, 2004 November 29-December 2, 2007 February 20-21, 2009 February 23-24, 2011 February 15-16 (Box 18, Folder 225-228)
- Fall Retreat, New Paltz, NY, 2005, 2008 (Box 19, Folder 229-230)
- Great Lakes Environmental Grantmakers, 2005 February 21-23, 2004-2005 (Box 19, Folder 231)
- Fall Retreat, Pacific Grove, CA, 2006 (Box 19, Folder 232)
- Fall Retreat, Santa Ana Pueblo, NM, 2007 (Box 19, Folder 233)
- Fall Retreat, Anchorage, AK, 2009 (Box 19, Folder 234)
- Fall Retreat, Monterey Bay, CA, 2010 (Box 19, Folder 235)
- Directory, 1989 January 3-June 22, 1990 July 15, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 236-239)
- Directory, 1992, 1994 April (Box 20, Folder 240-241)
- Grant Lists, 1988-1989 January, 1989 June-1991 December, 1992 March-1993 April (Box 20, Folder 242-244)
- EGA Updates, 1997-1998 (Box 20, Folder 245)
- EGA News & Updates, 1998-2001 Spring (Box 20, Folder 246-247)
- EGA News & Updates, 2001 Fall-2005 (Box 21, Folder 248-250)
- EGA News, 2006 (Box 21, Folder 252)
- EGA Journal, 2007-2009 (Box 21, Folder 253-254)
- A Guide to Trade and the Environment, Thomas A. Wathen, 1992 July (Box 22, Folder 255)
- Life After Rio, Conversations About UNCED and Where We Go From Here, 1992 (Box 22, Folder 256)
- Environmental Education, 2009 (Box 22, Folder 257)
- Climate Intersections, 2008 (Box 22, Folder 258)
- Investing for Impact, 2008 (Box 22, Folder 259)
- Solar Energy, 2009 (Box 22, Folder 260)
- Report from Cairo, A Grantmakers Guide to the United Nations International Conference on Population and Development (Box 22, Folder 261)
- Defining Sustainable Communities, 1994 June 2-4 (Box 22, Folder 262)
- Agriculture and the Environment, 1995 (Box 22, Folder 263)
- Annual Report, 2008 (Box 22, Folder 264)
- Green Beyond Grants, 2007-2008 (Box 22, Folder 265)
- Tracking the Field, Volume 2: A Closer Look at Environmental Grantmaking, 2009 (Box 22, Folder 266)
- Race, Poverty & the Environment, 1995 Fall (Box 22, Folder 267)
- Inclusive Practices Project, 1998, 2002 (Box 22, Folder 268)
- Real Change Partners, 2008 February 22 (Box 22, Folder 269)
- The White House, 1999 (Box 22, Folder 270)
- Grantmakeing Report, 1998 (Box 22, Folder 271)
- Environmental Grantmaking Foundations, 1999; 2011:014:001 (Box 22, Folder 272)
  Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist
- Environmental Grantmaking Foundations, 2000; 2011:14:002 (Box 22, Folder 273)
- Environmental Grantmaking Foundations, 11th Edition, 2011:14:003 (Box 22, Folder 274)
- Environmental Grantmaking Foundations, 2003; 2011:14:004 (Box 22, Folder 275)
- Environmental Grantmaking Foundations, 11th Edition, 2011:14:005 (Box 22, Folder 276)
  Separated Materials
  This is a monograph.
- Environmental Grantmaking Foundations, 2003; 2011:14:006 (Box 22, Folder 277)
  This is a monograph
- Capstone NY Wagner Graduate School of Public Service, 2011:14:007 (Box 22, Folder 278)
- Marketplace of Ideas-Road to Copenhagen, 2011:14:008 (Box 22, Folder 279)
- Paid Bills, Expenses, Checks, Deposits and Payments (Box 23, Box 24, Box 25, Box 26)
  Restricted - Financial material - Open in 2022.